The image data from the simulator
用 GPU 来处理模拟器生成的图像数据
is going to be much easier to work with on a GPU
要比使用 CPU 来处理
than on a CPU.
容易得多
So I've launched an AWS EC2 instance with an attached GPU.
这里 我启动了一个可使用 GPU 进行计算加速的 AWS EC2 实例
And I'm going to train the network there.
准备在这个实例上训练网络
I'll use SCP to copy the data up to the EC2 instance,
我会先使用 SCP 把数据传输到 EC2 实例
and then extract the data there.
然后在那上面提取数据
Next, I'll use Python CSV library to read and store
接下来 我使用 Python 的 CSV 库读取并存储
the lines from the drivinglog.csv file, then,
drivinglog.csv 文件
for each line, I'll extract the path to the camera image.
而后 从每行数据提取每个摄像头拍摄图像的路径
But remember that path was recorded on my local machine.
但请记住 这些路径是我本地机器上的路径
And now I'm on the AWS instance.
现在 我要在 AWS 实例上运行
So I'll need to update the path so it's valid here
所以我需要更新路径
on the AWS instance.
保证路径在 AWS 实例上是有效的
An easy way to update the path is
有一种方法可以轻松更新路径
to split the path on its slashes,
就是在斜杠（'/'）处分割路径
and then extract the final token, which
然后提取最后一个斜杠后的内容
will be the file name.
这部分就是文件名
Then, I can add that file name to the end
接下来 我就可以把这些文件名添加到
of the path to the image directory
AWS 实例上的
here on my AWS instance.
图像目录路径的末尾
Once I have the current path, I can
一旦获取了当前路径 我就可以
use OpenCV to load the image.
使用 OpenCV 加载图像
And once I've loaded the image, I
加载图像后 我就能
can append it to my list of images.
把它添加到图像列表中
I can do something similar for the steering measurements,
可以利用类似操作导入转向角数据
which will serve as my output labels.
然后把它们用作输出标签
It's actually going to be easier to load this steering
加载转向角数据实际上更简单一些
measurements, because there are no paths or images to handle.
因为不需要处理路径或图像
I simply extract the fourth token from the CSV line,
我只需从 CSV 文件的行中提取第四列内容
and then cast it as a float.
然后将其数据格式转换为浮点型
That gives me the steering measurement
这样即可获得这个时间点上的
for this point in time.
转向角数据
Then, I append that measurement to the larger measurements
接下来 我把这些转向角数据添加到测量数据集内
array, just like I did for the image.
就像对图像的操作一样
Now that I've loaded the images and steering measurements,
现在 我已经加载了图像和转向角数据
I'm going to convert them to NumPy arrays,
我把它们的格式转换为 NumPy 矩阵
since that's the format Keras requires.
因为这是 Keras 要求的数据格式
Next, I'm going to build the most basic neural network
下面 我来搭建一个尽可能简单的神经网络
possible, just to verify that everything is working.
只是为了确保整个流程的运行没有问题
This network is just going to be a flattened image connected
这个网络只是一个从扁平化的图像
to a single output node.
到单一输出节点的连接
This single output node will predict
这个单一的输出节点会预测转向角
my steering angle, which makes this a regression network.
因此这个网络是一个回归网络
For a classification network I might
对于分类网络
apply a softmax activation function to the output layer.
需要在输出层后添加了一个 softmax 激活函数
But in a regression network like this,
但在这种回归网络里
I just want the single output node to directly predict
我只需要这个单一的输出节点来直接预测
the steering measurement.
转向角大小
So I won't apply an activation function here.
因此 我在这里不用任何激活函数
With the network constructed, I'll compile the model.
网络搭建好后 就可以编译这个模型了
For the loss function, I'll use mean squared error, or MSE.
我选择均方误差作为损失函数
This is different than the cross-entropy function
这和我们之前用过的交叉熵函数不同
we've used in the past, again because this
因为这是一个回归网络
is a regression network instead of a classification network.
不是分类网络
What I want to do is minimize the error between the steering
这里我想做的是
measurement that the network predicts and the ground
尽量降低网络的预测值和真实数值
truth steering measurement.
之间的误差
Mean squared error is a good loss function for this.
这种情况下 均方误差是一种理想的损失函数
Once the model is compiled, I'll train it with the feature
模型编译完成后 就可以使用之前导入的特征和标签数据来训练模型
and label arrays I just built. I'll also shuffle the data
同样地 我会打乱数据的顺序
and split off 20% of the data to use for a validation set.
并留出 20% 的数据作为验证集
Finally, I'm going to save the trained model, so that later I
最后 保存好训练完的模型
can download it onto my local machine,
稍后就可以下载到本地计算机上
and see if it works for driving the simulator.
并查看它在模拟器中自动驾驶的表现
Let's train the model and see how it goes.
我们开始训练模型 看看情况如何
By default, Keras trains for 10 epoches.
默认情况下 Keras 会训练 10 轮
And I can see that the validation loss
我可以看到 验证数据集的损失函数值
decreases for the first 7 epoches,
在前7轮是不断下降的
and then starts climbing again.
而后开始上升
This is a sign that maybe I'm overfitting the training data.
这说明可能发生了训练数据的过拟合
Now it looks a little better.
现在看起来好了一点
Now, the validation loss decreases for almost all
几乎所有轮数的验证集损失函数值
of the epoches.
都在降低
Next, I'll download this model to my local machine,
接下去 我会把这个训练好的模型下载到本地计算机上
and see how well it drives the car in the simulator.
并查看它在模拟器中自动驾驶的表现如何